{"id":"2018_23","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"For who is God besides the Lord? And who is the Rock except our God? It is God who arms me with strength and keeps my way secure.\" â€“ 2 Samuel 22:32-33","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_23_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_2","questionText":"2. What from the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study impacted you most in the past week?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 1 Kings 1:1-27.\nNathan and Bathsheba exposed Adonijah's attempt to become Israel's king.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Kings","verse":"1:1-27"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_23_3","questionText":"3. What stands out concerning Adonijah's strategy to gain the throne? How did he take advantage of circumstances and gain the favor of others?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_4a","questionText":"4. a. What was King David's responsibility in this situation? As the prophet, what was Nathan's responsibility?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_4b","questionText":"4. b. What God-given responsibility presently requires your attention and action?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_5","questionText":"5. Where and with whom is God inviting you to step out and exercise the influence He has given you?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 1 Kings 1:28-53.\nDavid declared Solomon Israel's next king.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Kings","verse":"1:28-53"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_23_6","questionText":"6. What lessons do you learn from David's actions? How might those lessons also apply in your circumstances?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_7","questionText":"7. What was Jonathan's message, and what were the implications? Why did Adonijah's guests respond as they did?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_8","questionText":"8. Describe Solomon's response to Adonijah. Which qualities will you ask God to develop in you?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 1 Chronicles 22:1-19; 29:1-20.\nDavid made extensive preparations for the temple before his death.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"22:1-19"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"29:1-20"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_23_9","questionText":"9. What was most meaningful to you in David's charge and prayers for Solomon? How might you similarly encourage and/or pray for someone else?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_10","questionText":"10. What do David's words and actions reveal about his belief in God? How do these truths about God encourage you in your present circumstances?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_11","questionText":"11. How has or will David's views on giving impact the way you give?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read 1 Kings 2 with 1 Chronicles 29:21-25.\nSolomon received and acted on David's instructions.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Kings","verse":"2:1-46"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"29:21-25"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_23_12","questionText":"12. What spiritual and practical counsel did David give Solomon?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_13","questionText":"13. What determines when and how you respond to counsel from others?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_23_14","questionText":"14. What were the results of Solomon's response to David's instructions? What spiritual and practical lessons do you learn about work God entrusts to people? (See 1 Kings 2:12, 46.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"1 Kings","verse":"2:12"},{"book":"1 Kings","verse":"2:46"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Read 1 Kings 1-2 with 1 Chronicles 22, 29.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Kings","verse":"1:1-2:46"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"22:1-19"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"29:1-30"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_23_15","questionText":"15. How did this week's study impact the influence you desire to have on and the legacy you want to leave to others (family, church, community, etc.)?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}